Baibhav Nag

Date of birth: 12/11/1997 | Nationality: Indian | Gender Male | (+91) 8902797186 | nagbaibhav@gmail.com |

https://github.com/Baibhav-nag

https://www.linkedin.com/in/baibhav-nag-b0295b215? lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad flagship3 profile view base contact details%3B%2FNdgG5PLTvW5HptmAalCHO%3D%3D

Whatsapp Messenger: 8902797186

Neelkanchan ,Flat-A, Ground Floor,1/D, Raipur Road (East) Sulekha Jadavpur , West Bengal, 700032, Kolkata, India

About me: I am currently pursuing my masters in mathematics at Jadavpur University. My research interests lie at the intersection of machine learning, deep learning, artificial intelligence, computer vision and game theory. I have a deep love for data science and I am interested in learning it's applications in different domains of human life and society. I believe data science is the best combination of mathematics and computer science that will rapidly change the world in the years to come. I always look forward to challenges and have a passion to think critically and analytically to make best use of available resources in order to achieve maximum output. I believe everything is possible with the right guidance, motivation and determination.

WORK EXPERIENCE

07/09/2021 - CURRENT - Bangalore, India

RESEARCH INTERN IN AUTONOMOUS DRIVING DOMAIN(REMOTE INTERNSHIP) – INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Started working under Professor Roland Erik Hass in the domain of self-driving cars.

03/11/2020 - CURRENT - Kolkata, India

RESEARCH INTERN IN MIR(MUSIC INFORMATION RETRIEVAL) DOMAIN – DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, JADAVPUR UNIVERSITY

Worked on Speech Emotion Recognition(SER) and proposed an effective ensemble of MLP and CNN for efficient recognition of human speech emotion, under the mentorship of Prof. Sarbani Roy and Asif Iqbal Middya. Our paper has been submitted to the Neural Computing And Applications journal and is under major review now. Currently working on multimodal SER where aim is to effectively recognize human emotions from all possible modalities(audio and video).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2020 - CURRENT - Kolkata, India

MASTER OF SCIENCE(MSC) IN MATHEMATICS - Jadavpur University

Field(s) of study

Mathematics

83.6 % (1st year 1st semester)

2017 - 2020 - Kolkata, India

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE(BSC) IN MATHEMATICS - Jadavpur University

Field(s) of study

Mathematics

59.78 %

2014 - 2016 - Kolkata, India

HIGHER SECONDARY EXAMINATION(CBSE) - South Point High School

Field(s) of study

Science

93.4 %

Field(s) of study

• English, Bengali, Mathematics, Physical Science, Life Science, History, Geography

91.4 %

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Python, C, C++, SQL

INDUSTRY SKILLS

Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Data Science, Data Analytics

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Word | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Powerpoint | Zoom | Skype | LinkedIn | Outlook | Organizational and planning skills | Decision-making | Analytical skills | Good listener and communicator | Critical thinking | Motivated | Conflict resolution | Creativity | Strategic Planning | Gmail | Responsibility | Research and analytical skills

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): BENGALI

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
HINDI	C2	C1	C1	C1	B2
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

CERTIFIED COURSES

18/06/2021

Coursera deep learning in computer vision

Grade - 96.16 %

coursera.org/verify/M54PCJAXXSKE

25/02/2021

Coursera natural language processing

Grade - 94.23 %

coursera.org/verify/TG6P6NLGGR7U

24/01/2021

Coursera an introduction to practical deep learning

Grade - 90.92 %

coursera.org/verify/FBZRZ34LYELB

Coursera machine learning for all

Grade - 92.50 %

coursera.org/verify/TETJE7296KXK

01/11/2020

Coursera machine learning

Grade - 97.25 %

coursera.org/verify/NGEDXVSJVVR8

21/03/2021

Edureka data science workshop on analyzing pubg data

www.edureka.co/verify

08/04/2021

Analytics vidhya introduction to python

Certification ID - dcmzf9jvl3

22/05/2021

Google data analytics

Grade - 86.68 %

coursera.org/verify/T9GJN3JGJ4PY

21/06/2021

Udemy the complete self-driving car course(applied deep learning)

ude.my/UC-b3ad7fd4-371f-4df1-a4cb-fd8add0af6bb

03/2019

NPTEL basic linear algebra

Grade - 71 % http://nptel.ac.in/noc

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Singing, Playing the guitar, Painting, Reading books, Swimming